hi hi and welcome to new every day I'm
Hi Hi gratam et novis quotidie me
Jen and I'm Carrie and on today's show
Jen et Carrie me et ostende hodie
we're going to talk about being made new
erant 'iens loqui de novo facta
you've got mad skills now hone them
acuunt eorum artes iam nunc demum istaec nata ad insaniam convertunt
learn new skills or improve your
discere novum artes sive meliorem tuum
existing ones with online video
entibus in online video
tutorials and training from Linda calm
tutorials et educatio a Linda cessabit
through our special link at cat five dot
per peculiarem nostrum ad apicem quinque cattus
TV / Linda learn software technology
TV / Cornelius discere technology software
creative and business skills you can use
Vos can partum et negotium artes
today to help you achieve your
ad auxilium vobis consequi tua hodie,
professional goals join today and start
iungere initio proposita hodie et professional
learning will give you this chance to
haec facultas doctrina dabo tibi
try it absolutely free with unlimited
experiri liberum omnino habeant cum
access to all of the courses sign up now
Suspendisse cursus nunc omnes aditus
for free cat5 dot TV / linda
CAT5 gratis dat TV / Linda
alright welcome back thanks for tuning
Licuit recipiet gratiam hitur
in again last week gen came back she was
Ultima septimana tergo iterum gen factum erat
away all summer helping lead a Christian
ne aestas auxilium auferetur universa Christiana
camp and so we heard about her
et castra eius audivimus de
experience and this week we are we're
et usus sunt septem nos sumus
going to keep going talking about that
iens ut custodiant iens ut loqueris
but also one of the themes well the
sed etiam unum ex tam themata
theme of the summer for you was being
credo enim aestatis erat
made new in Christ right yes so what
Etiam sic, quod rectum est in Christo novum
were some of the things that you talked
fuerunt aliqui in vobis sunt qui loquebatur
about under that theme right kids so
adeo ut sub modo dextris hedos
every day we have a different theme sort
modo quodam alio quotidie
of to get across the point that we are
ut et per illud quod nos sumus
made new the theme verse was second
novus thema in secunda versum esset
Corinthians 5 17 therefore if anyone is
V XVII ad Corinthios si quis ergo est
in Christ the new creation has come the
venit autem in Christo nova creatio
old has gone and the new is here mmm
abiit veteris et novae adest mmm
don't you know Bibles make that sound
sonum facere nescitis Bibles
mm-hmm mmm second Corinthians 5 17
hmm, secunda ad Corinthios V XVII mm mmm
what's that the seven yo oh my goodness
quid heu mihi, quod septem io bonitatem
yes cc7 yeah and so one of the themes
Ita et de argumentis memini cc7
was that we are given a new way to see
datum erat, ut qui novo modo video
and actually what I would do is I would
et in facto est, ut quae volo facere
I know you're like she's moving on the
Scio vestri 'moving ex illa ut
set she's moving on the set what is she
set id quod est movere in illa destinatis
doing when she never does this before
Numquam ante hoc quod facere illa,
well aren't you don't even notice if
ne quidem animadverto si vos non bene
dice pintuck but this isn't going to
Ad hoc autem non est talis pintuck
talk about this but every day on the way
modo quotidie aliud loqui
to see ooh I put on these glasses okay
haec speculis videantur in purus posui ooh
isn't that cool yeah now many campers
yeah refrigescant, quae iam non multa campers
those are the wee ones they're like five
ut sis quasi ones quinque, quňd in illa sunt,
to seven SAR like pastor Chen those are
ut septem illi SAR sicut pastor Chen
3d glasses I like very good funny story
3D specula mihi placet admodum ridiculam fabulam bonum,
senior boys that's ages 12 to 16 day 3
quod pueri XII ad XVI diem III senior in saecula saeculorum
or 4 i'm wearing these because it's
aut IV horum gero, quod suus '
super heroes for supper so I'm Clark
Super heroes qui vervecinam istam, sic Im 'Clark
Kent that night effect glasses I have my
Kent nocte modum specula habeo
I have my black hoodie with Superman
Habeo nigri cum hoodie Superman
underneath so I can be like oh and they
Quis sicut possum simul et
I'm in line with the boys and they're
Sum in linea cum pueris et tu
like whoa those aren't real no oh it's
O verae et non sine illis, suus 'non amo Heus
really
rem
he really there's no lenses in them they
et illic 'realiter non est in eis sunt lentium
say 3d on the side I'm like either just
Im 'iustus amo aut ab ea parte, inquam 3d
I are totally out of lunch during chapel
Et sunt prorsus de prandium in capella
or so intent that they just didn't clue
Vivamus vel non iustum esse intentum
ants what it was the content with so
qualis fuit contenta formicae
riveting oh my goodness in amazed 3d one
O stupor adprehendit me in 3D una bonitas riveting
sec there's nothing wrong with my eyes
nihil mihi mali sec
so you put on this back so I put on the
Itaque sic induit induit retro
specs and I say you know what why do
et dicis quid cur eu arcu
people wear glasses Terry why do people
quid homines gerunt specula populi Handel
who are losses well because I kept
qui salvam habui dispendia
squinting like this and I couldn't see
et sic PAETULUS videre non poterat
very clearly in ever the edges were all
ipso scilicet in omni fossae labra semper
blurry and driving was slightly
et fuge leviter blurry
dangerous right so there's something
ut illic 'aliquid juris periculo
physically wrong with your eyes that
natura mali oculos
caused you to need an adjustment it's
eduxero vos postulo suus 'aequilibritatem
not all in my head well they're in my
omnes quoque sunt in meo capite sis meo
head you know what I mean it's not
caput tu scis quod non vult esse
psychosomatic no it's like and so I
sic suus 'non amo quod psychosomatic
would say to them well what would happen
bene dicere ad illos quid eventurum esset,
if I traded glasses with someone ah wow
nisi cum specula et operatus est in eis aliquis ah wow
this is amazing everything's in 3d haha
Hoc mirabile est, quae est in 3D haha
and I'm like oh you look good on you
O vos vultus, sicut et ego bono super te,
Thanks okay look hmm but I would be like
Hmm bene gratias autem vultus, sicut et ego
whoa these are dirty well yeah so it's
tam bene memini quae est sordidum ohe
caused me it feels really weird on my
fecit me realiter sentit fatum sit a me
face like there's something there that's
ut illic 'aliquid quod suus' non faciem
caused me not to see I said these do not
haec non videtis me fecit
help me something physical doesn't
Non mihi res corporalis agit
really help me and my eyesight I said if
vere auxilium me, et dixi, si visu
something if Kari takes these off she
hi, si quid off non accipit Kari
cannot see and I said so often we we put
posuit et nos debemus, non potest videre quod dixi et saepe
things on to adjust to adjust our site
quae ad adjust ad adjust in nostrum site
but Jesus gives us a new way to see he
Iesus autem dat nobis viam novam, et videre,
actually comes in and changes the way we
mutat in actu, et non in via
look at people because our he makes us
quoniam qui facit nos videre
new so I'm just going to trade these
Im 'iustus iens ut nova prompsisset
back because I feel really weird my yes
rursus, quia sic sentio vere fatum meum
and so one one of the things that I
et ideo quae de
would often do is
Saepe enim quid esset
I would take a drumstick and I would had
Ut et ego had sumo a clavicula
a ping-pong ball on that side and I put
ping-PUTEO pilam dedi inde
through and so I was like I having a sty
propter quod et ego eram hara
in my eye huh and I try to get close to
huh et oculi mei ad capto
them and they'd be like oh I'm gonna
O youd 'amo Im' agnus dei esse eos qui
like it away I'm like what's wrong
ut abs te amo Im 'quis' iniuriam
they're like you're gonna hurt me I'm
ut sis tu similis amet nocuerunt mihi sum
like why what's wrong there's nothing
cur tamquam mali nihil
wrong and they're like there's something
et malum ut sis illic 'aliquid
in your eye and the Bible talks about
loquitur de oculo tuo et Biblia
this concept of judging in Matthew 7 it
quod conceptum est iudicandi in Matth VII
says do not judge others or you will be
inquit, non judicas, aut aliis erunt tibi
judged you will be judged in the same
iudicabitur, non attendit ut non iudicemini apud eundem,
way you judge others and the amount you
et quantum tu enim iudicio
give to others will be given to you why
quare dabitur et aliis
do you notice the little piece of dust
pars autem vides festucam in paululum pulveris
in your friends eyes but you do not
in oculis tuis et non
notice the big piece of wood in your own
magnum enim lignum per quod animadverto tua
eye how can you say to your friend let
Quomodo tu dicis amicum oculis lux tuae
me take that piece little piece of dust
pars a me accipere, ut paulo fragmen pulvis
out of your eye look at yourself you
de oculo tuo et te ipsum intueri
still have that big piece of wood in
Adhuc enim, quod magnum lignum erigant in porrectum
your own eye you hypocrite first take
hypocrita eice primum accipe tibi oculus tuus
the wood out of your own eye then you
tunc lignum de oculo tuo
will see clearly to take the dust out of
scilicet ut de videbis quod pulvis
your friends I and I was like I said why
et sicut dixi amicos tuos: et ut quid me
is that important why is that important
quod magni momenti est, quia
that you take that thing out of your eye
illud, quod tu de oculo tuo
so our answer well one of them says well
dicit ergo unus ex illis tam bene respondere nostri,
so you can see clearly so you don't
sic ut non videre potest evidenter
judge so you don't make poor judgments I
iudicas, et non faciam iudicia pauperum
said well then what what should be the
Ergo id quod esse dicitur
first priority then when we actually are
prius ergo cum simus ii sunt
in relationship with people and they
et qui in necessitudinem cum
said you gotta look at yourself first is
Redditus est primum vultus dixerunt ad te
there something wrong on the inside that
est aliquid iniuriam de medio illius
causes us to see people differently
qui aliter facit nos videre,
because there's a physical change on the
quia ibi est mutatio corporalis est in
inside of my eyes that makes me not see
intra in oculis meis, qui me non videbo
clearly yes and so is there a spiritual
ita scilicet quod sic, et est spirituale,
issue that causes us not to see people
quod nos offendat, ne exitus ad populum
clearly is their pride is there a way
scilicet superbia autem sua non est ita
that we were raised like maybe we were
quod forte erant similes essemus
raised actually to show unkindness to a
erexit ipsum aequum censent ad ostendere
certain group of people to judge one sin
certum est iudicare inter coetus et populos peccatum
is worse than another so we yeah that
quod est peius quam aliud sic yeah
popular
popular
asian we cannot yes treat them a certain
Etiam aliquam non aliter Asiae
way yeah so it was very interesting to
ut modo memini valde interesting
have those those conversations with them
cum iis illa
to talk about the fact that how does
quod non modo loqui
Jesus give us a new way to see and the
Da nobis viam novam, et Jesum videre
Bible story that went along with it
Vulgate w historia, qui una cum eo abierunt
because I believe this was the teaching
Credo quod haec doctrina est
aspect so the Bible story that went
atras ad proelia Biblia fabula, quae ad
along with it was we talked about the
per nos loquebatur de erat cum eo
woman at the well okay we also talked
mulier tam bene de nobis et loquebatur
about Zacchaeus so Zacchaeus was a man a
Zachaee * de viro ita et vir erat Zachaee *
tax collector and nobody wanted to be
neminem voluit esse et publicanus
around that keas and woman at the well
tam in circuitu quam in femina et keas
she was ostracized by everyone she had
ab ipsa quoque omnis illa relegaberis
been married five times was not living
non est nupta erat, quinque temporum viventem
with man so they both had social issues
cum itaque homo tam sociali habuisse exitibus
that when their disciples or the
aut cum discipulis
teachers of the law saw Jesus uh
Vidit Jesus scribis et condemnabunt uh
interacting with the woman at the well
mulieri quoque per mutuo occurrant cum
in Zacchaeus they went whoa what are you
Heus tu quae irent in Zaccheus
doing what are you doing and Jesus
et Iesus agis, quid agis
simply he said to Zach yes I'm going to
simpliciter dixit quod sic Im 'iens ut Zach
hang out your house and he says to the
pendet, et dixit ad domum tuam
woman at the well would you give me a
mulier ad bene esse dabis mihi
drink of water he hittin but he invites
sed et aquam vocat Hittin
himself into fellowship with people that
qui se communicaverit
we would see as unworthy and Jesus looks
videatur indignus, et nos cum Jesu sublimes
past that First Samuel 16-7 says the
Primum ait Samuhel 16-7 praeterita
Lord does not look at the things that
At quae non Domini
people look at people look at the
at qui spectant ad populum
outward appearance but the Lord looks at
quæ parent Dominus autem intuetur procul
the heart and Jesus sees past Zacchaeus
et suspiciens Iesus videt, praeterita cordis
and his what sin because he was sinning
et quia peccare peccatum
he was stealing from people he was
qui furabatur de populo eius
basically working for the Roman
plerumque opus Romanis
government so nobody liked him and yet
et imperium nemo probaverunt et ipsum
there he is he runs ahead and he
ipse est qui praecedit et non fecit
positions himself and a place to see
video ubi se positura contineantur
Jesus and Jesus turned someone calls him
Iesus conversus et Iesus aliquis vocat eum
by name and it was the presence and love
et nomen eius in caritate et praesentia
of Jesus that brought repentance in his
Iesu, qui duxit in paenitentiam
life yes it wasn't Jesus sang Zacchaeus
quod sic vita ei Iesus non laudaverunt eum Zacchee
like I've seen you what you're doing get
sicut ego vidi; vos enim estis in peccatis vestris possidebit
down here come on it's time to repent
huc veniet tempus paenitentiae
yeah it was the love of Christ it was
yeah fuit caritas Christi fuit
the love coming yes I've calm salvation
salus venire, quod sic amor cessabit quia commune aut inmundum
has come to your house today yes and
Etiam hodie, et venit ad domum tuam
Zakia is totally repented yeah
Yeah Zakia est prorsus egissent paenitentiam
like he's he had the actions in keeping
sicut de actionibus, secundum quod ipse est
with repentance he's like if I've stolen
Ego similis si furto ablatum est et ductus pœnitudine
anything I'm gonna replace old and yeah
Im 'agnus dei aliquid reponere senex et yeah
so Jesus saw past the outward appearance
Sic olim vidit speciem
and saw the heart just like the woman at
et vidi sicut cor mulieris in tempore
the well when Jesus is he knew all about
tum quod Cum Jesus autem sciens quia omnia circa
her and he still asked her for a cup of
et adhuc in ea interrogavit ei calicem
water can I have a drink of water and
aquam mihi ad sorbendum praebe aquae
she's like if you knew who I was like
Si suus 'sicut illa quae scirem qualis eram
who I was or she said that and because
et quia illa, ut dicitur, aut quis eram,
she's like why you asked why me why
quae est sicut causa cur interrogavit quid mihi
asking me like cuz she knew that if he
rogabat me, ut cuz si non sciebant eum
knew who she was there was no way
Quis scit nullo modo esse quae erat
because he was a man he was a Jewish man
quia erat vir iudaeus
he was a teacher and like that was a big
qui fuit magnus magister quasi
no-no all three of those for him to be
nemo enim horum trium nullum esse
associating with her a Samaritan woman
adiungunt ei ea quæ sum mulier Samaritana
and yet there's Jesus saying yeah but if
et si illic 'Iesus autem dixit yeah
you knew who I was right and Jesus once
et statim Iesus autem sciebant, qui iure me
again did the exact same thing it was
isdem rursus idem quod
his love and warmth and an acceptance of
acceptatio ab amore sui est, algoris,
her that drew her to repentance because
ea quae hausit quod Deus paenitentiam ad eam
doesn't she go running off and say come
et veniunt et dicunt non ire neque sectemini
come and see the man who knew everything
venite, et videte hominem qui sciens omnia
about me come and see him I'm thinking
veni mecum et vide ego cogito super eum
if I had her background I would not want
cum ea background, si non vis
to be inviting people to come and meet
invitantur ut veniret obviam populo
the person who knows everything about me
et qui scit omnia de me
yeah so what was it then about Jesus
yeah Quid igitur fuit de Iesu
that caused disgrace yes he embodied and
isque pudor et insita causatur
in John chapter 1 says Jesus came full
Caput I venit Iesus dixit apud Johannem plena
of grace and truth and both of those
tam eorum gratia et veritate
work together perfectly in him because
eo perfectius cooperantur
he's God yeah that he was able to say
yeah ipse est Deus qui poterat dicere
truthfully you've had five husbands and
quinque enim viros habuisti et veraciter
the man you now with is not your husband
et nunc quem habes non est tuus vir
yeah and yet there was that grace there
yeah et gratiam quae ibi erat
yes and you know it's cool in both
et tu scis quod sic frigus suus 'in utroque
stories never ones just Jesus say are
Iesus autem dixit non iustus ones fabulas
you sorry for your sins are you going to
paenitet te pro peccatis vadis ad
repent in either sorry there's none of
paenitentiam contristati illic aut nulla
that that's true actually they are
quia verum est, quod sint actualiter
immediately repentant because of his
mox ob paenitentiam
love right which is so cool there is no
dilige iure nulla est refrigerium
like okay let's let's pray let's say
lets 'okay ut lets' narro et orate
we're sorry for our sins and and there's
et ibi est et non paenitet de peccatis nostris
a time and a place for that I have no
tempus et locus non est me
problem but i just find it very
sed tantum illud invenire problema valde
interesting that in both situation
interesting quae in utroque situ
when Jesus reached out and love and
et Iesus cum pervenisset, et diligitis
actually reached out in fellowship right
extenditque manum dextram communicatione actually
it's that meal thing there's something
ut illic 'aliquid quod suus' prandium
about meals with Jesus where people just
de qua populus sicut cibus est Iesus
come come to him when we eat invite
ut comedamus eum veni vocare
people over share the love of Jesus but
Iesus autem participes in homines caritas
the woman at the well the water
mulierem aquam puteum
Zacchaeus the meal Jesus invited himself
Zachaee * ipse invitavit ad prandium Iesu
to them and they responded which is like
responditque eis simile
it changes the way that we need to see
hoc modo mutat, quod postulo video
people that is not it's not about who
qui non est de populo ut, qui non
they are or their actions or their sins
vel suis, vel eorum actus sunt peccata
or anything like that it really is about
aut sicut aliquid, quod de ea re
what does Jesus see in their heart and
Quid enim videre Jesum, et in corde eorum
the fact is the Bible says that God
hoc est quod Scriptura dicit Dominus
created every person man and woman he
omnis homo est creatus vir et mulier
created them in His image why to have a
quod fecit ad imaginem habere
relationship with them and then in
deinde cum illis
second Peter says the Lord is not slow
Non tardat Dominus dicit Petri secundo
right because he wants all people to be
quia rectum vult omnes homines esse
saved he wants all people to have a
salvus erit omnibus velit se habere
relationship with him so when he looks
cum ergo vidissent eum despiciat
at people what we would say are that
at quod homines sint, qui diceret
Zacchaeus is or the moment the well we
Aut non tam Zachaei momentum
say oh that you know and Jesus like no
O quam dicunt Iesu nescimus: et quasi nihil
that's the one I died for yes yeah he
quod suus 'unus sum mortuus est enim quod sic se yeah
gives us new eyes to see them yes which
quod etiam facit nos videre oculorum
is just a very powerful tool that we as
secundum quod est instrumentum potentissimum
believers have that we are when we are
cum non credentibus, nos autem non sumus
made new when we are in Christ the old
factum est cum novus Christi in antiquis
way of God the old ways gone the new has
itineribus abierunt per viam Dei antiquum novus enim non habet
come that old way of seeing things can
quia venit antiquis res conspiciendi modum acquirunt potest,
be gone we can ask Jesus change the way
abiit Iesus mutare non possumus quaerere per viam
I see these people right that he does it
Video homines isti, qui recte facit eam
and he does change the way I look at my
et mutare non spectant ad viam meam
husband changed the way I look at my
vir mutaverunt vultus viam meam
sister change the way that I look at my
mutata in via soror mea, ut intueri
my students or my friends god I need you
alumni et amici mei Deus meus te requiro
to change the way i look at them so that
Et sic vide quomodo immutare
when I look at them I see you I see what
quid si intueri uidero
you want me to see not what I see
non videbo vos volo video me
because the thing is we have human eyes
est quia homo est in oculis habemus,
just like the passage in Matthew 7 says
sicut in VII dicit apud Matthaeum,
we have styes like we have these stick
sicut lignum styes habemus habentes
sticks in our eyes that prevent us from
haesit enim prohibet oculos
seeing clearly and Jesus like you got to
cum scilicet Iesu et surrexit similis tui est
get rid of those and they're the only
get rid illorum, et tu solus
way
ita
those planks those sticks can be removed
qui laquearibus haeret illis, non amoveatur
it's through the power of the cross in
id est, per virtutem crucis
saying we're coming before Jesus is
venit autem Iesus in conspectu erant 'dicens
saying oh Lord I look I I do not look at
O dixit Dominus ad me ecce II, non quaerere
people the way that I should whatever it
et sic factum est ut quicquid
is that's inside of me that causes me
id facit Ipsi intus enim de me, quod
whether it's pride insecurity fear of
incertum metu an superbia
rejection fear in general whatever it is
repulsae metu communiter quidquid
it causes me to look at this person in
haec faciat mihi homo in intueri
this way would you please forgive me
sic parce mihi non placet
root it out of me I want to be changed
eruendus est ex me cupio non mutatum
by your power I want to be made new in
tua virtus mea renovamini autem vis
the way I look at people help me right
populum ad auxilium te respice in via recta
and the cool thing is he does yep he
et frigus res est qui nec ipse yep
does so and you know God's guts love and
et sic non sciunt quod amor Dei ventrem
transforming power in her life doesn't
transformationis potens in vitam non habet
just end no you know we're being made
sicut scitis neque finem facta erant
new and head to His image day after day
Nova imago eius in capite, et de die in diem
with being renewed in the image of our
renovato ad imaginem
Creator yes and he's going to carry on
Et sic loquitur auctor gesturi
the good work he started until the day
opus enim bonum coepi usque ad diem
of Christ Jesus amen and you know I have
Amen Iesu Christi et nescio ego
a friend of mine who growing up her
quoniam amicus meus, qui in ea crescente
father was not kind to her and she
et pater non est ad eam
became a Christian after she was an
factus est autem post haec erat Christiana
adult and God so changed her heart
et Deus mutavit illi est adulta cor meum
towards her dad but didn't realize it
Pater autem in ea non cognoscunt;
until she had to go and see him he
quæ erat usque in illum, ut vadam, et videbo illum
wasn't well and she she was just acting
et non tam illa agendi modo
in obedience because she knew she needed
opus, quod ad obsequium et cognovi ea
to go see this man and when she saw him
Vidit hoc vir quod ire cum eo
the love of Christ filled her amen she
Amen ea ipsa caritas Christi repleti
was able to not on her own volition yes
quod sic voluntas moveatur a suo proprio non poterat
she said I it wasn't me but God allowed
Deus autem dixit mihi non erat, non licere
her to see him differently to see him as
aliter se videre quam videre
one who for whom Christ has died and one
pro quo Christus mortuus est, et nemo est qui
who needs to accept his love yes and
et quod sic amor eius, qui indiget accipere
forgiveness
dimittetur illi
yes because of that that hurt Jesus
sic ut quod de illa nocere Iesu
washed it away yeah he can give us when
et lavit nos a se Yeah
will you surrender that to him he comes
Sibi ergo deditionem venit
in through the power of the Holy Spirit
per virtutem Spiritus sancti
changes the way we see and just like
sicut videmus quod mutat in via
it's not as if we know it sometimes it's
aliquando suus 'suus' non quasi nos novimus
not so we're presented with that person
sic erant 'non cum hoc homine videas presented
again that we go whoa yes you
iterum, ut vadam vobiscum quod sic Heus
differently just so cool yeah so and
ita et aliter, ita refrigescant yeah
maybe you're watching this or listening
maybe tibi in hac aut audire
to this and thinking yeah Carrie and Jen
et hanc ratus memini Aliquam Portare
but you don't know my husband you don't
sed tibi ne mea sint, non vir tu facis
know you don't know what's going on you
quia tu non scire quid suus 'iens tibi
don't know my friend and hurt that that
non nocuerunt mihi amicum, et illum
she's caused or you don't know my wife
vel causa illa non uxor mea
whatever it may be mm-hmm but maybe it
sed fortasse qualecumque sit mm hmm
just takes asking the Lord to help you
capit iustus ad auxilium vobis Dominus postulantes
see them differently men not to stay in
videte ne aliter manere in ea
a relationship that's causing damage
quod suus 'a relatione damnum;
right oh but God can give you a new way
ius autem o Dominus unde tibi dare possit novus via
of seeing them I know he he can he has
Scio enim quia non potes de cum illis est
in my own life of watch how he's
quoniam ille animam suam in custodiam
transformed relationships in my own life
transformed relationes in vita sua
wyd changing the way that I look at
wyd changing exspecto ad me in via
people and by taking the sky or the
et ea, quae neque in caelo
plank out of my own I because sometimes
et trabem faciat de me quia nunc meae
we don't even realize it's there and
non etiam animadverto suus, et ibi
then by his power he comes and he deals
Et veniens in virtute agit
with he heals us as we then can look at
Cum ergo nos aspicere medeatur
people differently because we are made
quia non fiunt aliter populus
new embraced I think that happens in
quod fit per cogitare et novam amplectitur
relationship with him rate like as we
necessitudinem cum eo rate pro similitudine absque peccato
spend more time getting to know who we
ut cognoscat quem tempus terere
are in christ that he has made us new
Christus nos novum in se fecit
and forgiven us already of those sins
et peccatorum illorum iam Christo donavit nobis
yeah then that affords us the
yeah et qui praestat nobis
opportunity gives us the ability that's
quod opportunitas facit habiles
the other people amen that's good news
Amen, quod est bonum nuntium ad populum alterum
eh that's good news well let's pray all
annon omne id est bonum nuntium tam ora lets '
right Lord we are so thankful for your
dextera Domini et super communicatione vestra sumus,
good news we're so thankful God that you
Gratias ago Deo, quod est bonum nuntium sumus
made a way for us to come to you through
Sic fecerunt nobis per venire ad vos
Jesus Christ and they've given us new
Christum Jesum novi, et dedisti nobis
life and hope through him and a new way
et vitam novam spem
of seeing people and Lord no matter what
et cum de Domino, quod utcumque
our week has been we just give it over
hebdomadam nostri fuit super nos tantum dabit
to you lord please forgive us for
Obsecro ut obliviscaris tibi Dominus pro nobis:
looking at people in the way that we
respiciens ad populum ut in via
shouldn't maybe judging that because of
ne forte ob iudicandum
their looks or how much money they have
eorum quibus aut pecuniam
or things they've said or their past or
vel praeterito vel quae dixi
lifestyle choices but God those are
lifestyle choices autem illi Deus:
people whom you love and for whom you've
quem amas, tu et populus, quem
died so help us to lay our lives down
mortui sunt nobis ad vitam
for them in the sense that we will love
nam illa quae in sensu diliget
them love them Jesus your love cost you
illos amant illas Iesus amor sumptus es
everything so would you equip us to see
omnia et nos instruere velis videre
people in a new way and to love them as
qui diligitis eos, sicut et in nova via
you've called us to live that we might
tu habitas qui vocavit nos non sunt, fortitudinem
represent you Jesus to the world so we
respondeam ei Iesus si sic mundi
pray this in your powerful name Jesus
haec precor potens in nomine Iesu
amen amen amen all right we want to say
Amen Amen Amen omnia recte possumus dicere vis,
a special thanks to our partners so if
specialis gratias sociis nostris, ut, si
you go to our website new everyday TV
quotidie novum TV ad vos website
and click on partners you can see a
et sociis vos can click in video
variety of people who are involved in
quis adhuc dubitat quantum in varietate
making this show happen one of them is
Contingit autem hoc spectaculo eorum
amazon com another is Lynn little
amazon com alius Johannes sit minus
company the logo comfort little company
Integer dolor dolor modicam consolationem
you can have them design a logo mmm-hmm
Mmm mmm-logo consilium habere possitis
because sometimes that's one of the
quia ex hoc nunc
hardest things to do when you're trying
quae sunt maxime facere ut vestri 'trying
to you know brand something you need the
notam scio tibi opus est aliquid,
right logo so check them out also on our
ita etiam de nostra logo reprehendo
website is a link to family christian
link to website est Familia Christiana
stores as well so go to the website have
stores ita etiam ad habere website
a look and see who's sponsoring us or in
et respice et vide et in nos, qui suus 'patrocinio
partnership with us and check them out
arcebat de societate nobiscum
as well and have a wonderful week and
et quoque sabbati quod mirabilis est
have a wonderful chairs they are done
sedes habere mirabilia fiunt
cheers
iubentium
you
vos